Andy Brown iOS Developer

andybrown41@icloud.com · github.com/ab492 · 07591 454 148 · Putney, London

Profile

I am a self-trained iOS developer looking for an opportunity to move into a full-time developer role. My previous work experience includes working as a Visual Effects Data Coordinator in film and television. Over the last two years, however, I have been working in my spare time to study iOS development. I am proactive and detail-orientated, always working to ensure every job assigned to me is undertaken efficiently and to a high standard.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF EXETER, 2010-2013
First Class BSc. Honors Degree in Mathematics
BIRCHWOOD HIGH SCHOOL, BISHOP'S STORTFORD, 2003-2010
3 A-Levels (A*-A), 10 GCSEs (A*-C)

Portfolio

The two apps on my <u>GitHub</u> profile, *Skrilla* and *FlipFlopWeather*, demonstrate a number of key developer skills:

- **Self-motivation**: Developing these apps in my spare time involved persistence as I dealt with and learned from various problems, reading around issues I came across and asking for guidance on StackOverflow.
- Organisation: My projects are presented in as clear a way as possible with organised project files, comments on more complex methods and clear documentation on GitHub to ensure clarity for an outside reader.
- Technical skills: Design patterns such as MVC, MVVM and coordinators; data persistence; parsing JSON from an external API; writing clear data models; using 3rd party libraries; source control with Git. Each GitHub page lists more specific technologies used.

Employment History

'ALADDIN' - DISNEY - VISUAL EFFECTS DATA COORDINATOR,

APRIL 2017-APRIL 2019

Reference: Victoria Keeling (Visual Effects Producer)

My role was to manage all of the data generated throughout the two years of production. Responsibilities included:

- Tracking and distributing Director's notes on the thousands of shots and versions, requiring acute attention-to-detail in a high pressured environment to ensure nothing was missed.
- Point of call for technical issues within the department, working independently and taking initiative in problem-solving as and when issues arose while maintaining a cheerful attitude.

Employment History (Continued)

• The planning and implementation of a 4K screening room with a high speed connection to the US Disney team. This involved liaising with multiple International teams, requiring patience and proactivity to meet expectations within a very tight timeframe.

'LIFE' - SKYDANCE FILMS - VISUAL EFFECTS ASSISTANT, OCTOBER 2016-MARCH 2017

'LIFE' - SKYDANCE FILMS - PRODUCTION ASSISTANT, MARCH 2016-OCTOBER 2016

'FLOWERS SERIES ONE' - KUDOS PRODUCTIONS - PRODUCTION RUNNER, SEPTEMBER 2015-JANUARY 2016

PRINCESS PRODUCTIONS - OFFICE RUNNER AND PRODUCTION RUNNER, JANUARY 2015-SEPTEMBER 2015

Other Interests

In my spare time I love to cook and travel, recently spending a month travelling around Italy perfecting my pasta making. I'm also a keen runner, having completed two marathons. I enjoy keeping up with the latest technologies within the iOS and Swift world, but also technology in general. I've recently been interested in Solid, Tim Berners Lee's project to decentralise the web.